CHEN LIU

http://chenliucl.herokuapp.com https://linkedin.com/in/chenliuCL (C) 732-447-7457 lcdantechen@gmail.com

Front-end developer with proficient knowledge of a back-end programming language. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in various programming languages and graphic design skills. Strong background in project management and customer relations

SKILLS

Programming Languages

HTML5 · CSS · Bootstrap · Firebase · Javascript · JQuery · JSON · AJAX · Node.js

• Express.js • React.js • Mysql • MongoDB • Computer science fundamentals

Other technical skills

Graphic design • 3D modeling• Autodesk Maya • Animation • Adobe products (Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash, After Effects)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer Self-employed

January 2015 – Present

Union, NJ

- Join client meetings to learn about project scopes and discuss design options with outside-the-box thinking
- Create raw designs using Adobe products and/or Autodesk Maya
- Convert raw designs into CSS/HTML themes to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability
- Oversaw scheduling of project milestones and coordinated with clients on any challenges to be overcome

Web Developer

May 2014 – Present

Ravissanics, Inc.

East Brunswick, NJ

- Work with senior developer to complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code
- Ensure day-to-day continuity for the Ravissanics primary web property

Technical Sale Representative

January 2016 – Present

ZXChem, Inc.

Piscataway, NJ

Food Scientist

December 2014 – December 2015

National Bio+Green Sciences, LLC.

Branchburg, NJ

EDUCATION

Rutgers University

October 2016

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Rutgers University

May 2015

Masters of Science, Food Science

HONORS/AWARDS

First winner: IFTSA Product Development 2014 – Heart Healthy

March 2014